Imagine a place where your neighbors greet your children by name;
تخيلوا مكانا يحيّي فيه الجيران أبناءكم بأسمائهم
a place with splendid vistas;
مكانا تحيط به مشاهد خلابة؛
a place where you can drive just 20 minutes
مكانا يمكنك القيادة فيه لمدة 20 دقيقة
and put your sailboat on the water.
وتضع مركبك الشراعي على الماء.
It's a seductive place, isn't it?
إنه مكان مغر، أليس كذلك؟
I don't live there.
أنا لا أعيش هناك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But I did journey on a 27,000-mile trip
ولكنني قمت برحلة لمسافة 27,000 ميل
for two years, to the fastest-growing and whitest counties in America.
لمدة سنتين، لأكثر المقاطعات في أمريكا ازدهاراً ويسكنها البيض.
What is a Whitopia?
ماذا نعني بمدن البيض؟
I define Whitopia in three ways:
أفسر مدن البيض بثلاث طرق:
First, a Whitopia has posted at least six percent population growth since 2000.
أولا، سجلت مدن البيض زيادة بنسبة %6 على الأقل في عدد السكان منذ سنة 2000.
Secondly, the majority of that growth comes from white migrants.
ثانياً، تعود هذه الزيادة السكانية لعدد المهاجرين البيض.
And third, the Whitopia has an ineffable charm,
و ثالثاً، تملك مدن البيض سحرا فائقا لا يوصف،
a pleasant look and feel,
ومظهرا ساحرا وإحساسا.
a je Ne sais quoi.
لا أعرف كيف أصف ذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
To learn how and why Whitopias are ticking,
لاكتشاف طريقة سير الحياة في مدن الييض وكيفية تقلبها،
I immersed myself for several months apiece in three of them:
قسمت وقتي لاكتشاف كل واحدة منها:
first, St. George, Utah;
أولاً ، سانت جورج، يوتا؛
second, Coeur d'Alene, Idaho;
ثانياً: كيردالين، أيداهو؛
and third, Forsyth County, Georgia.
و ثالثاً: فورسيث كاونتي، جورجيا.
First stop, St. George -- a beautiful town of red rock landscapes.
أول محطة هي ساينت جورج -- مدينة جميلة بتضاريس صخرية حمراء.
In the 1850s, Brigham Young dispatched families to St. George
في عام 1850، أرسل بريغهام يونغ عددا من العائلات إلى ساينت جورج
to grow cotton because of the hot, arid climate.
لزراعة القطن بسبب الحر والمناخ الجاف.
And so they called it Utah's Dixie, and the name sticks to this day.
أطلقوا عليها اسم "جنوب يوتا" وقد بقي هذا الاسم عالقا بها إلى يومنا هذا.
I approached my time in each Whitopia like an anthropologist.
ضبطت وقتي في كل مدينة وكأنني عالِمٌ بِالأَنْثُروبولوجْيا.
I made detailed spreadsheets of all the power brokers in the communities,
وضعت جدولا مفصلا حول صانعي القرارت السياسية بالمجتمع،
who I needed to meet, where I needed to be,
من يجب أن أقابل، أين أحتاج أن أكون،
and I threw myself with gusto in these communities.
واندمجت في هذه المجتمعات بلباقة وذوق.
I went to zoning board meetings,
حظرت اجتماعات مجلس الإدارة ،
I went to Democratic clubs and Republican clubs.
ذهبت لنوادي أحزاب ديمقراطية وأخرى تابعة لأحزاب جمهورية.
I went to poker nights.
ذهبت لبعض مجالس لعب البوكر.
In St. George, I rented a home at the Entrada,
قمت باستئجار منزل في سانت جورج باينترادا،
one of the town's premier gated communities.
واحدة من أول المجتمعات المسورة.
There were no Motel 6's or Howard Johnsons for me.
لم يكن يوجد هناك موتيل أو فندق هوارد جونسون يأويني.
I lived in Whitopia as a resident, and not like a visitor.
سكنت في مدن البيض كساكن وليس كزائر.
I rented myself this home by phone.
استأجرت هذا المنزل عن طريق الهاتف.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Golf is the perfect seductive symbol of Whitopia.
يعتبر لعب الغولف في مدن البيض طريقة للإغراء وجذب الانتباه.
When I went on my journey,
عندما انطلقت في رحلتي،
I had barely ever held a golf club.
كنت بالكاد أرتاد نوادي الغولف
By the time I left, I was golfing at least three times a week.
ومع مرور الوقت، أصبحت ألعبه ثلاث مرات في الأسبوع على الأقل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Golf helps people bond.
يساعد الغولف الناس على تمتين العلاقات.
Some of the best interviews I ever scored during my trip were on the golf courses.
كانت أفضل المقابلة التي أجريتها طيلة رحلتي في ملاعب الغولف.
One venture capitalist, for example, invited me to golf in his private club
فمثلا، قام واحد من أصحاب المشاريع الرأسمالية بدعوتي إلى ناديه الخاص
that had no minority members.
حيث لا وجود لأعضاء ينتمون لأقليات.
I also went fishing.
ذهبت أيضا لصيد السمك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Because I had never fished, this fellow had to teach me
ولأنني لم أكن قد اصطدت من قبل، فقد توجب على هذا الزميل تعليمي
how to cast my line and what bait to use.
كيفية إلقاء الخيط ووضع الطعم.
I also played poker every weekend.
كما لعبت البوكر في نهاية كل أسبوع.
It was Texas Hold 'em with a $10 buy-in.
كانت لعبة تيكساس هولديم بقيمة شراء تبلغ 10 دولارات.
My poker mates may have been bluffing about the hands that they drew,
كان رفاقي في لعبة البوكر يخادعون ويكذبون بشأن الأوراق التي يملكونها
but they weren't bluffing about their social beliefs.
ولكنهم كانوا صريحين بشأن معتقداتهم الاجتماعية.
Some of the most raw, salty conversations I ever had
بعض أكثر الأحاديث صراحة واللاذعة التي حصلت
during my journey were at the poker table.
طيلة رحلتي، كانت على طاولة البوكر.
I'm a gung ho entertainer.
أنا مضيف في شركة للترفيه.
I love to cook, I hosted many dinner parties, and in return,
أحب طهي الطعام فكنت أنظم حفلات عشاء، ومقابل ذلك
people invited me to their dinner parties,
يقوم الناس بدعوتي لحفلات العشاء،
and to their barbecues, and to their pool parties,
وحفلات الشواء وحفلات السباحة الخاصة بهم،
and to their birthday parties.
وحفلات عيد الميلاد.
But it wasn't all fun.
ولكن لم يكن الأمر ممتعا تماما.
Immigration turned out to be a big issue in this Whitopia.
فقد تبين أن الهجرة تمثل مشكلة كبيرة في مدن البيض.
The St. George's Citizens Council on Illegal Immigration
قام مجلس المواطنين بسانت جورج حول الهجرة غير الشرعية
held regular and active protests against immigration,
بتنظيم احتجاجات منتظمة وناشطة ضد الهجرة،
and so what I gleaned from this Whitopia is what a hot debate this would become.
وما اكتشفته من هذه المدن هو أن هذا من شأنه أن يصبح جدالا لاذعا.
It was a real-time preview, and so it has become.
كانت هذه لمحة فورية وهو ما حدث.
Next stop: Almost Heaven, a cabin I rented for myself
المحطة الثانية هي كوخ استأجرته يحمل اسم "الجنة تقريبًا"
in Coeur d'Alene, in the beautiful North Idaho panhandle.
في وسط كويور دي أليني، في بانهاندل ايداهو الشمالية.
I rented this place for myself, also by phone.
استأجرت هذا المكان عن طريق الهاتف أيضا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The book "A Thousand Places To See Before You Die" lists Coeur d'Alene --
يحتوي كتاب " ألف مكان يجب زيارته قبل موتك" على كويور دي أليني--
it's a gorgeous paradise for huntsmen, boatmen and fishermen.
تعتبر جنة رائعة لكل من القناص والبحار وصائدي السمك.
My growing golf skills came in handy in Coeur d'Alene.
تحسنت هناك مهاراتي النامية في لعب الغولف.
I golfed with retired LAPD cops.
لعبت الغولف مع رجال الشرطة المتقاعدين من شرطة لوس أنجلوس.
In 1993, around 11,000 families and cops
في 1993، هرب حوالي 11،000 أسرة ورجل شرطة
fled Los Angeles after the L.A. racial unrest,
من لوس أنجلوس بعد الاضطرابات العنصرية التي حدثت،
for North Idaho, and they've built an expatriated community.
إلى ايداهو الشمالية، حيث تم بناء مجتمع المغتربين.
Given the conservatism of these cops,
وبالنظر لمدى حيطة هؤلاء وحذرهم،
there's no surprise that North Idaho has a strong gun culture.
ليس من الغريب أن تملك هذه الولاية ثقافة حمل الأسلحة.
In fact, it is said, North Idaho has more gun dealers than gas stations.
في الواقع، يتداول أن عدد تجار الأسلحة في شمال ايداهو يفوق عدد محطات الوقود.
So what's a resident to do to fit in?
إذا ما الذي يتوجب على المقيم هناك أن يفعل ليتكيف مع الوضع؟
I hit the gun club.
وصلت لنادي السلاح.
When I rented a gun, the gentleman behind the counter
عندما قمت باستئاجر سلاح، كان الرجل الموجود خلف المنضدة
was perfectly pleasant and kind,
لطيفا وكريما للغاية،
until I showed him my New York City driver's license.
إلى أن أريته رخصة القيادة المستخرجة من نيويورك.
That's when he got nervous.
عندها انتابه شعور بالقلق.
I'm not as bad a shot as I thought I might have been.
لست سيئا في الرماية كما كنت أعتقد.
What I learned from North Idaho is the peculiar brand of paranoia
ما تعلمته من شمال ايداهو هو وجود نوع من جنون الارتياب والشك
that can permeate a community when so many cops and guns are around.
الذي يمكن أن يسيطر على المجتمع عند انتشار رجال الشرطة والسلاح من حولهم.
In North Idaho, in my red pickup truck,
في شمال ايداهو، وداخل سيارتي البيك-أب الحمراء،
I kept a notepad.
كنت أحتفظ بمذكرة في داخلها.
And in that notepad I counted more Confederate flags than black people.
تتضمن هذه المذكرة الأعلام الكونفدرالية أكثر من الأشخاص السود.
In North Idaho, I found Confederate flags
في شمال ايداهو، وجدت الأعلام الكونفدرالية على
on key chains, on cellphone paraphernalia,
سلاسل المفاتيح والأشياء المتعلقة بالهاتف المحمول،
and on cars.
وحتى على السيارات.
About a seven-minute drive from my hidden lake cabin
على بعد سبع دقائق بالسيارة من كوخي السري على البحيرة
was the compound of Aryan Nations,
يوجد مجمع تابع لاريان نايشنز،
the white supremacist group.
وهي مجموعة تدعو إلى هيمنة العرق الأبيض.
America's Promise Ministries, the religious arm of Aryan Nations,
صادف أن"وزارات الوعد الأمريكي" أو الجيش الديني لمجموعة اريان نايشنز،
happened to have a three-day retreat during my visit.
صادف أن كانت خلال زيارتي في حالة انعزال لمدة ثلاثة أيام.
So I decided to crash it.
فقررت اقتحامها.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I'm the only non-Aryan journalist I'm aware of ever to have done so.
أنا الصحفي الوحيد غير المناصر لهم، أدرك أنني لم أقم بهذا من قبل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Among the many memorable episodes of that retreat...
من بين العديد من الوقائع التي لا تنسى من ذلك الانعزال..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
...is when Abe, an Aryan, sidled up next to me.
هي عندما جلس بالقرب مني آب، وهو من أعضاء اريان.
He slapped my knee, and he said, "Hey Rich, I just want you to know one thing.
ربت على ركبتي وقال لي: "ريتش، أود منك فقط أن تعرف شيئا واحدا.
We are not white supremacists. We are white separatists.
نحن لسنا متعصبين حيال البيض، إنما نحن نحب الانفصال عن الآخرين.
We don't think we're better than you,
لا أعتقد أننا أفضل منك،
we just want to be away from you."
إنما نريد فقط الابتعاد عنك."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Indeed, most white people in Whitopia are neither white supremacists
في الواقع، أغلب الذين يعيشون في مدن البيض يكونون إما عنصريين
or white separatists;
وإما انفصاليين؛
in fact, they're not there for explicitly racial reasons at all.
لم يكونوا موجودين هناك لأسباب عنصرية صريحة على الإطلاق.
Rather, they emigrate there
بالأحرى، هاجروا إلى هناك
for friendliness, comfort, security, safety --
من أجل تكوين الصداقات والتمتع بالراحة والأمن والأمان--
reasons that they implicitly associate to whiteness in itself.
أسباب مرتبطة ضمنيا بالعرق الأبيض بحد ذاته.
Next stop was Georgia.
كانت وجهتي التالية جورجيا.
In Georgia, I stayed in an exurb north of Atlanta.
في جورجيا، عشت في مسكن جماعي شمال أتلانتا.
In Utah, I found poker;
في يوتا، وجدت لعبة البوكر؛
in Idaho, I found guns;
في ايداهو، وجدت السلاح؛
in Georgia, I found God.
و في جورجيا، وجدت الرب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The way that I immersed myself in this Whitopia
الطريقة التي اعتمدتها للاندماج في هاته المدينة
was to become active at First Redeemer Church,
هي أن أصبح ناشطا في كنسية "المخلّص الأول"،
a megachurch that's so huge that it has golf carts
وهي كنيسة ضخمة جدا توجد بها عربات الغولف
to escort the congregants around its many parking lots on campus.
لنقل المصلين حول ساحات وقوف السيارات العديدة الموجودة بحرمها.
I was active in the youth ministry.
كنت ناشطا في وزارة الشباب.
And for me, personally, I was more comfortable in this Whitopia
وبالنسبة لي شخصيا، كنت أشعر براحة في هذه المدينة
than say, in a Colorado, or an Idaho, or even a suburban Boston.
لنقل أكثر من كولورادو أو ايداهو أو حتى ضواحي وسطن.
That is because [there], in Georgia,
ويعود ذلك هناك، في جورجيا،
white people and black people are more historically familiar to one another.
إلى أن السكان البيض والسود تربطهم تاريخيا علاقة ومعتادون ببعضهم البعض.
I was less exotic in this Whitopia.
كنت أشعر بنسبة أقل من الغرابة في هذا المكان.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But what does it all mean?
ولكن ماذا يعني كل ذلك؟
Whitopian dreaming, Whitopia migration, is a push-pull phenomenon,
يعتبر كل من حلم العرق الأبيض وهجرة العرق الأبيض ظاهرة دفع وجذب،
full of alarming pushes and alluring pulls,
مليءٌ بدفعات مثيرة للرعب ولحظات جذب مغرية،
and Whitopia operates at the level of conscious and unconscious bias.
وتعمل مدن البيض على مستوى التحيز الواعي واللاواعي.
It's possible for people to be in Whitopia not for racist reasons,
يعتبر وجود الأشخاص في مدن البيض بدون أي أسباب عنصرية واردا،
though it has racist outcomes.
رغم أنه يؤدي إلى النتائج عنصرية.
Many Whitopians feel pushed by illegals,
يشعر العديد منهم بأنه تم تجاهلهم بسبب المهاجرين غير الشرعيين،
social welfare abuse, minorities, density, crowded schools.
اعتداءات على الرعاية الاجتماعية والأقلية والكثافة السكنية وازدحام المدارس.
Many Whitopians feel pulled by merit,
يشعر العديد منهم بأنهم مسكونون بالجدارة
freedom, the allure of privatism -- privatized places, privatized people,
و الحرية وإغراء الخصخصة-- من أماكن وأشخاص
privatized things.
وأشياء .
And I learned in Whitopia how a country can have racism
وتعلمت في مدن البيض أنه يمكن أن نجد العنصرية في بلد
without racists.
بدون وجود العنصريين.
Many of my smug urban liberal friends
لم يستطع العديد من أصدقائي الليبراليين والمغرورين الحضريين
couldn't believe I would go on such a venture.
تصديق أنني سأذهب في مثل هذه الرحلة.
The reality is that many white Americans are affable and kind.
في الحقيقة أنه يوجد العديد من الأمريكيين البيض دمثو الأخلاق ولطفاء.
Interpersonal race relations -- how we treat each other as human beings --
تعبر العلاقة العرقية في التعامل مع الآخرين -- كيف نعامل بعضنا البعض كبشر--
are vastly better than in my parents' generation.
أفضل بكثير مما كانت عليه في عهد والداي.
Can you imagine me going to Whitopia 40 years ago?
هل يمكنك أن تتخيل زيارتي لمدن البيض قبل 40 عاما؟
What a journey that would have been.
ويا لها من رحلة لو حدثت.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And yet, some things haven't changed.
ولكن لم تتغير بعض الأمور إلى الآن.
America is as residentially and educationally segregated today
بقيت أمريكا على حالها إلى الآن دولة سكنية ومعزولة تربويا
as it was in 1970.
كما كانت عليه في عام 1970.
As Americans, we often find ways to cook for each other,
كأمريكيين، نجد لأنفسنا طرقا للطبخ لبعضنا البعض،
to dance with each other,
للرقص مع بعضنا البعض،
to host with each other,
لاستضافة بعضنا البعض،
but why can't that translate into how we treat each other as communities?
ولكن لماذا لا يمكن ترجمة ذلك إلى كيفية معاملة بعضنا البعض كمجتمعات؟
It's a devastating irony,
إنها لمفارقة مدمرة،
how we have gone forward as individuals,
كيف يمكننا أن نسير إلى الأمام كأفراد،
and backwards as communities.
ونتراجع الى الوراء كمجتمعات.
One of the Whitopian outlooks that really hit me
صدمتني وجهة نظر شخص من مدن البيض
was a proverbial saying:
والتي كانت عبارة عن قول مأثور:
"One black man is a delightful dinner guest;
" يعتبر الرجل الأسود بمفرده ضيف عشاء مبهج؛
50 black men is a ghetto."
أما 50 رجلا أسود فهم غيتو (حيّ الأقلية)."
One of the big contexts animating my Whitopian journey was the year 2042.
قام سياق من السياقات الكبيرة بانعاش رحلتي لمدن البيض، وهو عام 2042.
By 2042, white people will no longer be the American majority.
بحلول عام 2042، لن تبقى الأغلبية الأمريكية من البيض.
As such, will there be more Whitopias?
على هذا النحو، هل سيوجد المزيد من مدن البيض؟
In looking at this,
عند النظر إلى هذا،
the danger of Whitopia is that the more segregation we have,
يعتبر خطر وجود مدن للبيض أنه كلما زادت التفرقة الموجودة
the less we can look at and confront conscious and unconscious bias.
تضاءلت إمكانية رؤيتها ومواجهة الانحياز الواعي واللاواعي.
I ventured on my two-year, 27,000 mile journey
قمت بمغامرة لمدة عامين، و هي رحلة لمسافة 27،000 ميل،
to learn where, why, and how white people are fleeing,
لأتعلم أين ولماذا وكيف يهرب البيض؟
but I didn't expect to have so much fun on my journey.
لم أتوقع أنني سأستمتع كثيرا خلال رحلتي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I didn't expect to learn so much about myself.
لم أتوقع أنني سأتعلم الكثير عن نفسي.
I don't expect I'll be living in a Whitopia --
لم أتوقع أنني سأسكن في مدن البيض--
or a Blacktopia, for that matter.
أو مدن الاشخاص السود من أجل ذلك.
I do plan to continue golfing every chance I get.
أخطط لمواصلة لعب الغولف كلما سنحت لي الفرصة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I'll just have to leave the guns and megachurches back in Whitopia.
وسيكون علي فقط ترك المسدسات والكنائس العملاقة في مدن البيض.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)